<p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">A process flow chart of the preparation of submicron LLZNO powder and the sintering of LLZNO ceramics is showed in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="materials-13-00560-f001">Figure 1</xref>. LLZNO powder was synthesized by the conventional solid-state reaction [<xref rid="B44-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>]. Lithium hydroxide monohydrate (LiOH&#183;H<sub>2</sub>O, 98%, Xilong Scientific Co., Ltd., Shantou, China), lanthanum oxide (La<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, 99.99%, Shanghai Aladdin Bio-Chem Technology Co., Ltd., Shanghai, China), zirconia (ZrO<sub>2</sub>, 99%, Shanghai Aladdin Bio-Chem Technology Co., Ltd., Shanghai, China), and niobium oxide (Nb<sub>2</sub>O<sub>5</sub>, 99.99%, Sinopharm Chemical Reagent Co., Ltd., Shanghai, China) were used as the raw materials and 10 wt% excess of LiOH&#183;H<sub>2</sub>O was added to compensate for the lithium loss in the high-temperature calcination and sintering process. Yttrium stabilized zirconia (YSZ, 4~8 mm in diameter) and isopropanol (IPA) were used as the ball-grinding medium. The ratio of raw material to grinding balls was 1:5 and the mixed raw material powder was wet-ball ground at 800 rpm in the planetary ball mill for 6 h. The mixture was dried at 70 &#176;C for 14 h, then calcined at 950 &#176;C for 12 h in an alumina crucible with ambient air to obtain the cubic-phase LLZNO powder. LLZNO slurry was attrition milled (Shanghai ROOT mechanical and electrical equipment Co., Ltd., Shanghai, China, 0.7 L volume, 70% filling rate) at 1000 rpm for 2 h, taking YSZ (0.4 mm in diameter) and IPA as the grinding medium, and the solid&#8210;liquid ratio was 1:5. The LLZNO slurry was dried at 70 &#176;C for 14 h to obtain submicron LLZNO powder, from which green pellets (mass of 3 g, 19 mm in diameter and a thickness of about 4 mm) were pressed at 200 MPa under a cold uniaxial press. After that, the green pellets were sintered in a muffle furnace (Changsha Yuandong Electric Furnace Factory) without mother powder at 1100&#8211;1200 &#176;C for 30&#8211;360 min and then cooled down naturally. At the same time, the green pellets were put on a platinum wire and placed in a crucible of MgO with the lid on to prevent impurity migration and a large amount of volatilization of lithium during the process of high-temperature sintering. For further testing, LLZNO ceramic pellets were polished with 400 and 1000 mesh sandpaper.</p>