<p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">In order to test the electrochemical performance of submicron LLZNO powder, we prepared a composite cathode and assembled quasi-solid-state batteries. The composite cathode consisted of a LiMn<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub> positive electrode layer and a submicron LLZNO electrolyte layer. The positive electrode was fabricated by coating the slurry of a mixture containing LiMn<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub> powder, submicron LLZNO powder, acetylene black (Shanghai Hersbit Chemical Co., Ltd., Shanghai, China), and polyvinylidene difluoride (PVDF, FR905, Shanghai San ai fu New Material Technology Co., Ltd., Shanghai, China), with a weight ratio of 7:2:1:1, onto circular aluminum foils (thickness of 20 &#181;m, Shenzhen Kejingstar Technology Ltd., Shenzhen, China) as the current collector, and the positive material loading was 1.66 mg/cm<sup>2</sup>. Then the composite cathode was fabricated by coating the slurry of a mixture containing submicron LLZNO powder and Polyvinylidene Fluoride (PVDF) with a weight ratio of 9:1 onto the positive electrode layer. The composite cathode was punched into disks with 18 mm diameters after compacted by a roller press (Shenzhen Kejingstar Technology Ltd., Shenzhen, China), and the density of composite cathode was about 2.5 g/cm<sup>3</sup>. Quasi-solid-state batteries were assembled with two electrode coin cells (type CR-2025) in a glove box filled with argon and with lithium metal foil (15 mm in diameter and 1 mm thick, Shenzhen Kejingstar Technology Ltd., Shenzhen, China) as the negative current collector. In addition, 20 &#181;L of a liquid organic electrolyte (1 M LiPF<sub>6</sub> dissolved in ethyl carbonate (EC) and dimethyl carbonate (DMC) with a ratio of 1:1, CAPCHEM, Shenzhen, China [<xref rid="B45-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">45</xref>]) was added to improve the contact and reduce the interface impedance between the submicron LLZNO electrolyte layer and the anode/cathode [<xref rid="B46-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">46</xref>,<xref rid="B47-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">47</xref>]. Compared with lithium-ion batteries, the added amount of liquid organic electrolyte was small [<xref rid="B48-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">48</xref>,<xref rid="B49-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">49</xref>].</p>