<p xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">Currently, lithium-ion batteries are widely used in electric vehicles (EVs), hybrid electric vehicles (HEVs), computers, smart grids, wearable devices, etc. [<xref rid="B1-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">1</xref>]. Traditional lithium-ion batteries have organic liquid electrolytes which easily burn and explode under abusive conditions. In addition, with the development of modern society, lithium-ion batteries have gradually moved toward high specific energy. Researchers have studied cathode materials, such as LiCoO<sub>2</sub>, LiMn<sub>2</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, LiFePO<sub>4</sub>, LiNi<sub>0.6</sub>Co<sub>0.2</sub>Mn<sub>0.2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>, LiNi<sub>0.8</sub>Co<sub>0.1</sub>Mn<sub>0.1</sub>O<sub>2</sub>, LiNi<sub>0.8</sub>Co<sub>0.15</sub>Al<sub>0.05</sub>O<sub>2</sub>, and xLi<sub>2</sub>MnO<sub>3</sub>&#183;(1 &#8722; x)LiMO<sub>2</sub>, to increase the energy density of lithium-ion batteries [<xref rid="B2-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>,<xref rid="B3-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">3</xref>,<xref rid="B4-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>,<xref rid="B5-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">5</xref>,<xref rid="B6-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>,<xref rid="B7-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>,<xref rid="B8-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">8</xref>]. The energy density can be improved by increasing the charging voltage, which will lead to serious side reactions and safety issues. In order to solve the safety problem of lithium-ion batteries, researchers have turned their attention to all-solid-state lithium batteries, which use inorganic electrolytes. The non-flammability, long cycling life and wide electrochemical window of all-solid-state lithium batteries are considered to provide the high safety and high energy density of the next-generation energy storage systems [<xref rid="B9-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>,<xref rid="B10-materials-13-00560" ref-type="bibr">10</xref>].</p>